JORGE E. SOSA

6462 ELLA LEE LN 2 HOUSTON, TX, 77057 281-919-5907

JORGEDUARDO.1994@GMAIL.COM

Freelance Front End Web Developer with one year experience, mainly creating single page web apps. Basic knowledge of common database languages such as MySQL and MongoDB. Will graduate with a B.S in computer Science on December 2017. Looking to improve as a front end web developer and develop skills to become a full stack web developer.

Professional Experience

DESIGN AND FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

Language Ambassadors, LLC. April 2017 – May 2017

- Responsible for building the company main web page.
- Designed and implemented web-based user interface using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, directed front end project from concept to completion.
- Responsive design using mainly Bootstrap.
- Back-End simple implementation for contact section using PHP
- Brand management: slogan, look & feel of the website.

Travesia: Influencer Group, June 2017 – July 2017

- Designed and implemented web-based user interface using HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, jQuery, directed front end project from concept to completion.
- Logo designed and created using Adobe Illustrator.
- Responsive design using mainly Bootstrap.
- Directed photoshoot for pictures in the website.
- All communication was done remotely since Travesia was located in Colombia.

ADMISSIONS OPERATIONS ASSISTANT

Admissions Operations Office at University of St. Thomas. Houston, TX August 2013 to Present

- Assisted with processing of applications and other documents as they are received by the Office of Undergraduate Admissions.
- Updated student information in PeopleSoft or CRM software.
- Filed physical files and documents as applications are processed.

Education

B.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE

University of St. Thomas, Houston TX. December 2017

- Scholarship Recipient.
 - Dean's List Junior and Senior Years.
 - Co-Founder and Vice President of the UST Computer Science Club.

Additional Skills

- HTML 5, CSS SCSS SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap proficiency.
- Basic NodeJS, Basic PHP, Basic ReactJS knowledge.
- Fluent in English, Spanish and Italian.
- Experience using Linux command line.
- Experience using GitHub.
- Basic knowledge on Photoshop and Adobe Illustrator.